Gilbert Ssenyonjo

gssenyonjo@gmail.com +256 703 51 2563

https://linkedin.com/in/rsgilbert

SUMMARY

Full Stack software engineer with 4 years of professional experience.

Microsoft certified professional in Azure, Dynamics 365, Power Platform.

Working fulltime for HRP Solutions as a software developer and part-time for Synaptic Solutions (Tanzania) as a senior software engineer.

Co-founder of Pakasa Holdings, a limited liability company offering AWS services and implementing software applications that leverage AWS technology.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, TypeScript, JavaScript, AL

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Dataverse, MySQL, MongoDB

Tools: Powershell, Git, node.js

Platforms: Dotnet, AWS, Azure, Power Platform

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SYNAPTIC SOLUTIONS, 6TH MAY 2024 - PRESENT

Address: Dar es Salaam, Tanzania

Position: Senior Software Engineer, Part-time

Summary: Synaptic Solutions is a Microsoft Certified partner operating in Tanzania,

Kenya, Zambia, Rwanda and Burundi.

Duties and Responsibilities:

Tender Management System

Description: I am developing a tender management system for our client World Wide Foundation Zambia.

Purchase Requisition Portal

Description: I developed a web portal for purchase requisitions for client WWF Tanzania.

Sales application integrated with ZRA

Description: I am currently working on a sales application that has to be integrated with ZRA for invoice fiscalization for our Zambia clients.

HRP SOLUTIONS (U) LTD, 1ST SEPT 2020 - PRESENT

Address: Plot 49, Ntinda Road, +256 392 004 312, https://hrpsolutions.com

Position: Software Engineer, Full-time paid

Summary: HRP Solutions is a Microsoft Gold Certified Partner specializing in

delivering ERP software solutions in East and Central Africa.

Duties and Responsibilities:

Integration of stock exchange system for U.S.E

Projection Description: I integrated the stock exchange system used by U.S.E with their financial system so that brokers and custodians get invoiced automatically.

Clients: Uganda Securities Exchange

Integration of Hospital with Jubilee

Projection Description: I integrated the hospital management system used by C-Care's IMCs with Jubilee's Claim Management System so that claims are sent electronically.

Clients: C-Care

Bank Integrations

Description: Integrating client financial software systems with several banks so that payments are sent automatically to the bank. Banks include Stanbic bank, Citibank, ABSA, Stanchart.

Clients: UWA, IDRC, Mildmay, UDB, UEGCL

Sales application for Kawacom Uganda

Description: I implemented a sales software application used by Kawacom Uganda.

The app is used to invoice their customers, both local and abroad.

Clients: Kawacom Uganda

Integration with Core Banking system

Description: I am currently working on an integration between the core banking system used by Uganda Development Bank with their new reporting system.

Clients: Uganda Development Bank

Implementation of Sales Electronic Tax Register application used in Burundi

Description: Implemented a Sales Electronic Tax Register software application that is used in Burundi. The system is integrated with the Burundi Government's Electronic Billing Machine so that invoices issues are fiscalised in real-time.

Clients: Gardaworld Burundi

Implementation of a Web API used for Bookings and Reservations (UWA)

Description: I implemented a Web API that is used by the Bookings and Reservations

System to track bookings, invoices, payments and rescheduled.

Project Duration: Involvement: 6th Oct 2023 – 16th November 2023

Clients: Uganda Wildlife Authority

Integration with URA Electronic Fiscal Devices (EFD)

Description: Implemented pulling invoices generated by EFDs from URA to client's

ERP

Clients: Oshochemicals Uganda

Integration with Tanzania's Virtual Fiscal Device

Description: Integrating MS Dynamics BC180 with Tanzania's Virtual Fiscal Device using the Power VFD platform to automatically send invoices to the government

Clients: Tracknav Tanzania

Leave Management System

Description: Implemented a web application that is used by employees to apply for

leave

Clients: AVSI Uganda

Electronic Payment System

Description: Implemented a web application that is used by Mildmay to process

salaries for their district staff and community personnel

Clients: Mildmay Uganda

Timesheets system

Description: Implemented timesheets functionality in a human resource

management system

Clients: Makerere University Walter Reed Project (MUWRP)

Integration with HxCentral (Pulse) feedback system

Description: Implemented sending of patient visits and admission data to HxCentral

to collect feedback from patients

Clients: International Hospital Kampala, International Medical Centre

Integration with Smart Printing Management System (SPMS)

Description: Implemented sending of released production orders to SPMS for

printing

Clients: Riley Uganda

Integration with National Drug Authority Management Information System (NDAMIS)

Description: Implemented a web API that is consumed by NDAMIS to send invoice

and payment data to client's ERP

Clients: Riley Uganda

Window Server Migration

Description: Migration from Windows Server 2008 R2 to Windows Server 2019

Clients: Riley Uganda

EFRIS API Integrations

Description: Performing an integration between the local tax authority in Uganda

and Microsoft Dynamics

Clients: Uganda Batteries Limited, Kawacom (U) Limited, Uganda Wildlife Authority

etc (About 20 customers)

Sub-Grant Management System (SGMS)

Description: A web application that allows the donor (Mildmay Uganda) to track the

activities of her Sub-Grantees **Clients**: Mildmay Uganda

, 3

Timesheets Web Application

Description: A web application that allows the employees to fill in and submit their

month timesheets **Clients**: AVSI Uganda

Integration with Lab Information Management System

Description: Integration of the Hospital Management Information System (HIMS)

with the Lab Information Management System (LIMS)

Clients: IMC, IHK (Now called C-Care)

Integration with Beyonic

Description: Integration of Microsoft Dynamics NAV with Beyonic

Clients: Mildmay Uganda

IT CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

• Microsoft Certified: Power Platform Functional Consultant Associate

Microsoft Certified: Power Platform Solution Architect Expert

Microsoft Certified: Dynamics 365 Business Central Functional Consultant

Associate

EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science, Makerere University Kampala, Kampala, Uganda 08/2017 – 01/2022. CGPA is 3.48

UACE, St. Marys College Kisubi. 16 points

UCE, Ndejje Senior Secondary School, 9 in 8 aggregates.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- Microsoft Power Platform Functional Consultant, Koenig Solutions, India, 25th
 Sept 2023 29th Sept 2023
- Microsoft Power Platform Solution Architect, Koenig Solutions, India, 2nd Oct 2023 04th Oct 2023

HOBBIES

- Playing chess on lichess.org
- Playing scrabble with friends
- Football
- Going to cinema

HONORS

Certificate of Participation in the 2017 International Mathematical Olympiad, Brazil